Finding Aid for First Presbyterian Church (Blissfield, Mich.) records, 1845-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Presbyterian Church (Blissfield, Mich.) records
1845-1977
First Presbyterian Church (Blissfield, Mich.).
86827 Ba 2
Session minutes, minutes of the board of trustees, Sunday school records, papers of women's association, the ladies church society, and the women's home missionary society.
7 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the church (donor no. 1183 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Presbyterian Church in Blissfield, Michigan was founded in 1829.
The record group includes session minutes and minutes of the board of trustees. In addition, there are extensive records for the church's Sunday school and for various women's organizations, including the women's association, the ladies church society, and the women's home missionary society. Annual reports, newsletters, and church bulletins provide details on church activities.
Subjects:
Missionaries--United States.; Monteith, John, 1788-1868.; Women--Michigan--Blissfield--Societies and clubs.; Home missions--United States.; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Blissfield.
- Minute books, membership materials
  - Session minutes, May 16, 1845-January 24, 1951
    - May 16, 1845-April 1868 (Box 1)
    - May 31, 1903-March 7, 1920 (Box 1)
    - January 23, 1921-January 24, 1951 (Box 1)
      (on indefinite loan to the donor)
  - Minutes of the board of trustees, 1879-January 9, 1961
    - 1879-March 31, 1941 (Box 1)
    - March 30, 1942-January 9, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Church register, circa 1845-1958 (Box 1)
  - Membership roll prior to, 1965 (Box 1)
    (also includes mailing lists, etc.)
  - Minutes of the Civic and Religious Federation of Waitsburg March 1912-February 1914 and Blissfield church roll, 1931-1938 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Blissfield Ministerial Association, November 1928-October 1958 (Box 1)
    (Vol. II)
  - Certificates of Dismission and Reception (stubs), September 1917-August 1955 (Box 1)
  - Secretary's book of the Y.P.S.C.E., August 1901-April 1904
    - August 1901-July 1903 (Box 1)
    - September 1903-April 1904 (Box 1)
- Sunday School Records
  - Secretary's record, 1904-1918 (Box 2)
    - 1904-1909 (Box 2)
    - 1909-1914 (Box 2)
    - 1915-1918 (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's record, 1920-1921 (Box 2)
  - Cash book, 1893-1894 (Box 2)
  - Librarian's book, 1850-1967
    - 1850-1853 (Box 2)
    - 1853-1855 (Box 2)
    - 1856-1858 (Box 2)
    - 1863-1867 (Box 2)
  - Attendance records, 1873-1968
    - 1873-1874 (Box 2)
    - 1876-1877 (Box 2)
    - 1879 (Box 2)
    - 1881 (Box 2)
    - 1883-1884 (Box 2)
    - 1884 (Box 2)
    - 1885-1886 (Box 2)
    - 1894-1896 (Box 2)
    - 1921-1925 (Box 2)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 2)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - 1960 (Box 2)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    - 1964 (Box 2)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - 1966 (Box 2)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Presbyterian Aid Sunday School roll, 1921-1925 (Box 2)
- Women's organizations
  - Women's Association
    - Secretary's book, 1922-1969
      - 1926-1935 (Box 3)
      - 1935-1940 (Box 3)
      - 1940-1946 (Box 3)
      - 1946-1950 (Box 3)
      - 1951-1956 (Box 3)
      - 1957-1960 (Box 3)
      - 1960-1969 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, including constitution and yearbooks (Box 3)
  - Women's Home Missionary Society
    - Secretary's book, 1893-1917
      - 1893-1898 (Box 3)
      - 1898-1902 (Box 3)
      - 1902-1906 (Box 3)
      - 1906-1908 (Box 3)
      - 1911-1913 (Box 3)
      - 1908-1917 (Box 3)
    - Treasurer's book, 1888-1920
      - 1888-1901 (Box 3)
      - 1901-1914 (Box 3)
      - 1914-1920 (Box 3)
  - Ladies Church Society
    - Minutes, 1879-1924
      - 1879-1906 (Box 4)
      - 1906-1918 (Box 4)
      - 1918-1924 (Box 4)
    - Cash book, 1880-1923 (Box 4)
  - Young Ladies Guild, 1916-1919 (Box 4)
  - Sewing Society secretary's book, 1852-1861 (Box 4)
  - Records of the Priscilla Circle, 1961-1967 (Box 4)
  - Records of the Afternoon Circle, 1951-1957 (Box 4)
  - Yearbooks of church organizations (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  - Quit-claim deed to First Presbyterian Society, 1884 (Box 4)
  - Building Projects, 1950s; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Miscellanea (Box 4)
- Treasurer's Records
  - Cashbook of the Presbyterian Church and Society, 1877-1909
    - 1877-1892 (Box 5)
    - 1896-1909 (Box 5)
  - Treasurer's book, 1948-1954 (Box 5)
  - Collections for Missions, 1914-1917 (Box 5)
  - Collections for Missions, 1923 (Box 5)
  - Cashbook, 1914-1922 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1917-1924
    - 1917-1923 (Box 5)
    - 1923 (Box 5)
    - 1923-1924 (Box 5)
- Bulletins, reports, etc.
  - Annual reports, 1954-1972 (Box 6)
  - "Lifeline"--church newsletter (Box 6)
  - Bulletins, 1949-1977 (Box 7)
    (1973-1974 missing)